Jack Staffen

New York, NY, 10014 | 917-881-6989 | jack.staffen@gmail.com GitHub: jastaffen | Linkedin

Full Stack Software Engineer

Experience building Full Stack web applications using JavaScript and JavaScript frameworks like React, Redux, and React Native in the frontend, and Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and SQL in the backend.

Pursuing music and audio engineering/production gave me considerable experience striking the balance between the immense technical knowledge and boundless creativity required for the job.

I am excited to employ this unique balance that is also intrinsic to software engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript: JavaScript (ES6), React, React Native, React Navigation, Redux

Ruby: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord **Web & Data:** HTML, CSS, SQL, Postgres

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Gust -Github: Frontend, Backend | Demo

An app where users can vote on songs they want a particular artist to perform live, can follow those artists, and can discover their followed artists' upcoming shows.

- Built the frontend using React Native to make an ios-friendly mobile app with an intuitive user interface with React
 Navigation and built the backend using Ruby on Rails as an API with PostGres to manage, store, and control data
 & its flow.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Managed client-side state data using the Redux library.
- Retrieved data from the Spotify API and SongKick API so users could search for artists, albums, and tracks, and find upcoming concerts by artists they follow, respectively.
- Recorded user's geolocation, and translated that geolocation into an address using the Google Maps API.

Motel Home Music Site - Github | Demo

A simple portfolio site showcasing my music scoring, design, and audio editing work.

- Constructed the site with React and React Router.
- Utilized flexbox and CSS animations to build an interactive and responsive user interface.
- Followed wireframes made by a graphic designer that employ a minimalist/internet brutalist aesthetic.

EXPERIENCE

Front Person in Jack and Eliza and Purr

11/2015 - Present

- Composes, records, and performs original music nationally and internationally.
- Manages, organizes, and leads rehearsals, performances, and general day-to-day band goings on.

Co-founder of Motel Home Music

11/2015 - Present

- Produces and records commercial musical scores for digital ads and independent films.
- Communicates and coordinates with clients to cater to their wants and needs and construct the desired product.
- Manages finances and taxes.

Private Music Teacher

09/2016 - 09/2018

• Taught guitar, vocals, drums, and piano to children between the ages of 7-12.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 10/2019 - 01/2020

An immersive, highly intensive web development program that accepts around 6% of applicants and has a 93% placement rate Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering Track

New York University Graduated 05/2017

Bachelor of Arts from Gallatin School of Individualized Study (with a concentration in Art History, Political Science, and the Social Sciences)

Cumulative GPA - 3.78